えっへへ はは ははは…
Wait for me!
-あはは あはは…
-待ってよー
とおー！
わっはー！
Hey, you can't go sprinkling it like that!
-えーい うんっ えい え？
-あーあ そんな撒き方しちゃダメだよー
What's the matter?
どうしただに？
It's the way Uwh was sprinkling the
field medicine Hakuoro-san made!
ウーが ハクオロさんの作った
畑に撒く薬を…
If you sprinkle it like that,
it'll be gone in no time!
あんな撒き方してたら
すぐに 無くなっちゃうよー
S... Sorry...
うほう すまん
Oh, it's all right.
まぁ いいじゃねーかー
If we run out, we'll just go make more!
無くなったら また作りゃー
You know how to make it?
親父 作るやり方 知ってるか？
Sure, just leave it to me!
おぉ 任せとけっ
The kid told me how to!
あんちゃんから
バッチリ作り方聞いといたあ
-へえー
-おおー
Well, he did teach me, but...
I don't remember it all too well.
んやあ はずだが…
あまり よく覚えてねぇ
えぇぇ
どぅっはははは
Next time I go to the castle,
I'll have him make me some more!
今度また城に行った時 あんちゃんに
作ってもらえばいいだろう
Wait a minute, dear!
-ちょっと あんた！
-いいいー
Hakuoro is this country's emperor now!
ハクオロは 今じゃ
この国のオゥルォ（皇）なんだよぉ
You can't go bothering him
with something like that!
そんなこと 気楽に頼んで
いいわけないだろう？
Don't worry.
えぇ 心配ねえってえ
No matter how important he becomes,
the kid's not gonna change.
あんちゃんなら どんなに偉くなったって
変わっちまったりしねーさ
Yeah, I think so too, but still...
そりゃあ たしだってそう思うさあ
It's just that Hakuoro has
his duties as king.
でもねぇ ハクオロには
オゥルォとしての政があるんだよ
I know, I was just kidding around.
分かってるさあ
ちょっと冗談で言ってみただけだって
That reminds me, I wonder how
Eruruu and Aruruu are doing?
にしても エルルゥとアルルゥたち
どうしてるかねぇ？
Oh, I'm sure they're all having
a grand, old time together.
そりゃきっと あんちゃんと一緒に
皆で楽しくやってるさあ
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空 果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に 充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼（はね）を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ 行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから 一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
Everlasting Promise
We have returned, sire.
只今戻りました
Thank you for your efforts.
ご苦労さまでした
How did it go?
いかがでしたか？
はい
They gladly agreed.
皆さんに 快く承諾してもらいました
They are even willing to attend the ceremony
for the signing of the alliance.
調印の儀にも 来ていただけるとのこと
Brother, what's this alliance
ceremony all about?
兄者 調印の儀って…
ニウェに対抗するために
近隣諸国と同盟を組むことにしたのだ
In order to fight against Niwe, we're forming
an alliance with the neighboring countries.
それでウルトリィに
使節になってもらった
I asked Urutori to be our envoy.
Shikeripechim won't be able
to attack as easily now.
これでシケルペチムも
簡単には攻めて来ないはずです
I see, then we won't be waging any
more wars for a while, will we?
そうかあ
じゃあ 当分 戦は無いってことだな
ちーっとばかり退屈になりやすねえ
Might be a bit boring though.
-バカ言うなあ
-ん？
Don't be ridiculous!
It's best for a country and its
people to be without war!
国と民にとって
戦が無いのが一番だろうに
Yeah, right!
とか何とか言ってえ
I bet you're just relieved that you
don't have to fight Niwe!
ニウェと戦わなくて済むから
ホッとしてるんじゃねえのかあ？
I heard you got your ass whipped real good.
聞いたぜ ズタボロに やられたってなあ
What? That was only because
I got caught off guard!
あの時は 不意を突かれたからだあ
And look who's talking! You're always having
Benawi coming to your rescue!
大体 貴様こそ
いつもベナウィに守ってもらいやがって
I'm back!
ただいまあ
Welcome back.
お帰りなさい
Was it fun?
楽しかった？
Yeah, a lot of fun!
うーん とっても！
Oh yeah, here are some souvenirs.
わー そうだ
これ お土産
Here, Aru-chan.
はい アルちゃん
えへ
でえ ユズっちには これね
And this is for you, Yuzu-cchi.
うふっ
I hear a sound from far away.
遠くで… 音が… 鳴っています
That's the sound of the ocean.
海の音だよ
ふーん
The sound of the ocean?
海の… 音？
お水がね いっぱいあるの
It's a place with lots of water.
Is it a pond?
お池ですか？
ううん もっと ずーっと いっぱい
No, it's got way, way more water.
A huge amount, as far as the eye can see!
すごい量が 見渡す限りあるんだよ
はーい あはは…
あはあ…
クッシャアナウヤマ
オンアビタウンヌテスクル
Kussha anaumaya on wabitaun Tuskuru,
hamante yabakuku hondoru taisai
ハマンテ ヤパクク ホンロロ タイサイ
ヌシシュ マウタラン
シエワッカ トゥスクル
nushishu mautaran shiewakka Tuskuru
eyeo makoru yana.
イヨマカ オルヤナ
我ら奉りし御神ウィツァルネミテア
We, the Onkami Witsalnemitea present this.
では ここに印を
Now, place your seal here.
御神ウィツァルネミテアの下
By the grace of our god, Witsalnemitea,
place your seal of alliance...
ここに調印の儀を
誰だ 貴様
Who are you!?
You are in the presence of His Highness!
Stand back!
御前である 下がれ！
えーい どけー！
Get outta my way!
それどころじゃ ねんだよ！
I don't have time for this!
Pops!
親父さん
あんちゃん 敵襲だ！
Kid! We're under attack!
何だと？
What!? Is it Shikeripechim!?
シケルペチムか？
どこの どいつか知んねえが
いきなり襲って来やがったんだよ
I don't know who the heck they are.
They attacked us all of a sudden!
It seems they saw an opening in our defenses
どうやら 調印の儀の
警備のために動かした軍の
when we moved our troops to guard
the alliance ceremony.
隙を突かれてしまったようですね
They're right at our front door! Hurry, Kid!
奴らは すぐそこまで来てやがる
急げ あんちゃん
How's everyone?
What of all the others?
皆は？
他の皆は無事なのか？
んっえ しんぺいすんな
Don't worry. They all escaped a while ago.
皆 とっくに逃げおおせたさ
んなことより 急げっ！
So forget about that! Now hurry!
We're going!
出るぞ
Right!
おう！
御意
Get ready!
Take Aruruu and Yuzuha and go to
the back of the castle.
アルルゥとユズハを連れて 城の奥に
Yes!
はい
親父さんも早く避難してくれ
Pops, you need to evacuate too!
いやー
Nah, I'm beat after running all this way.
ここまで走って来て
さすがに疲れちまったあ
I'm gonna rest up a bit first, then go.
俺は ちーっと休んでから行くわぁ
All right.
分かった
Kid!
あんちゃん
んぐ 負けんなよ
Don't you lose!
Right!
敵襲ー！ 急げ！
うっ いやああーーっ！
敵 捕捉！
Enemy troops approaching!
来ます！
Shall we close the gates?
門を閉じますか？
いや あれを使う
No, we'll use "them".
Are they ready?
準備はできているな？
うぃっす
Yes, sir.
とぅやーー！
うぅーやあー！ うやーー！
おおーわあーーっ！
Do it!
今だ！
Archers forward!
ペリエライ（弓衆） 前へ！
Blue Team, take aim!
青組 構え！
Red Team, take aim!
紅組 構え！
でやーー！ わあーー！
Fire!
撃てえ！
These aren't soldiers from Shikeripechim.
彼ら シケルペチムの兵士ではありません
Then where are they from?
いったい何者だ？
It's futile to continue!
Drop your weapons!
これ以上は無駄だ！
武器を捨てろ！
いやー！ うぉー！
Blue Team, second wave, take aim!
青組 第２波 構え！
Red Team, second wave, take aim!
赤組 第２波 構え！
撃てえ！
Fire!
でっへへ
Just when I thought he was getting
the hang of being king...
すっかりオゥルォの
貫禄ってやつが出てきたと思ったけど
He's still got a way to go though.
まーだまだ
Yep, the kid still needs us.
やっぱ あんちゃんは
俺たちが一緒じゃねえとなあ
まぁ エルルゥとアルルゥが一緒なんだ
Well, at least he has Eruruu
and Aruruu with him.
It'll work out all right.
何とかなんだろう
Boy, this time, I'm really tired.
しかし
今度ばかしは さすがに疲れたぜえ
I'm getting kinda sleepy...
何か 眠くなって…
来やがったあ
Honey! You came to get me?
母ちゃーん
むけえに来てくれたのか？
How was it?
どうでい
ちゃんと 約束は守ったぜ
I kept my promise.
何でい
Hey, you guys are here too?
おめえたちも来てたのかぁ
んじゃあ けえるとすっか
Well then, I guess I'd better get going also.
皆で また ぱーっとやろうぜえ
We can all have a good time together again.
So long, you take care now, Kid.
じゃあな
頑張れよ あんちゃん
What is going on?
どういうことだ
They knew their surprise attack had failed.
奇襲に失敗したというのに
Why didn't they try to retreat?
なぜ引こうとしなかった
Don't think...
Don't think this is the end of it!
これで これで終わりだと思うなあ
我らの この恨み
Our comrades will surely avenge us
and relieve this bitterness!
必ず
同胞が晴らしてくれるう！
苦しめえ
Suffer...
へぇ 貴様の苦しみこそが
Your suffering shall become our bliss!
我らを至福に導く
わーっははは… あっははは…
Who were these men?
こいつらは…
いったい…
Pops...
親父
親父ー
What's wrong?
C'mon wake up Pops.
親父
起きる
Please?
親父
Why didn't he tell us then?
なぜ
あの時
Please don't blame yourself.
そんなに ご自分を責めないでください
誰も気付けなかったのですから
Nobody else realized either.
I'm back.
今 戻りやした
Good work.
ご苦労でした
What is your report on the situation?
現状の報告を
We believe the enemy has
withdrawn from the area.
敵は既に撤退したと思われ
There were no signs left of them.
一帯に敵影は ありやせんでした
How was Yamayura?
ヤマユラは
What kind of condition was the village in?
あの集落は どうなっていた？
Well... That is...
それは… その…
Are you sure?
いいんですか？
Yes...
Understood. Then here is my report.
分かりやした
報告しやす
The fort surrounding the settlement showed
signs of having been breeched,
集落の周囲に防壁が積まれ
and there were signs that there
had been a struggle...
奴らと交戦したものと…
Never mind the details!
回りくどいことは いい
Tell me the results. What happened?
結果は
どうなった？
The village had been burned to the ground.
集落は炎上
As for survivors...
生存者…
There were none.
ありやせん
We were born and raised in Yamayura,
俺たちゃ 生まれも育ちも
ヤマユラだからなあ
だから 死ぬ時も…
so we'd like to die there too.
Please wake up! Pops!
親父
親父ー
Aruruu, let him be, okay?
アルルゥ
もう そっとしてあげるんだ
Why? He's just sleeping.
どうして？
親父 寝てる
He's gotta wake up.
寝てるだけ…
Pops... will not be waking up again.
親父さんは もう
目を覚まさないんだ
He won't wake up?
起きないの？
Yes.
He's gone to where Tuskuru-san is.
トゥスクルさんの所へ 行ったんだよ
He's with Grandma?
おばあちゃんの…
とこ？
That's right,
along with everyone else.
皆と
一緒に
はぁふぅ
ふーん
No, Pops wake up! Please!
親父！
起きる
起きる 親父！
Don't go away. Please wake up!
Pops!
親父
-アルちゃん…
-起きる！
Aru-chan...
あはぁ は…
くぅふぅ
ふぁぃ… くふぅ…
Aruruu, that's enough.
アルルゥ
もういい
Stop, Aruruu.
やめるんだ
No...
やだ
Aruruu...
アルルゥ
No, no, no, no!
やだ
う ひっ う ひっ やだ やだ ひっ
やーだあー！
NO!
ひっ えっ んん やあー うーん
Eruruu?
エルルゥ
I've put her to sleep with some medicine,
お薬で眠らせたんです
before her heart is crushed by
the weight of her sorrow.
悲しみで心が
潰されないように はぁー
Eruruu!
エルルゥ
I'm okay.
私は大丈夫です
I'm all right...
大丈夫ですから
Benawi...
ベナウィ
Sire!
奴らが何者かの 調べはついているな
You've looked into who those
men were, correct?
Based on their armor and belongings,
we're certain they were from Kuccha Keccha.
鎧や遺品から クッチャ・ケッチャの者に
間違い無いと思われます
Brother! Give me the order to
mobilize against them!
兄者
俺に奴らの討伐命令を！
We must not.
いけません
We should not make any move until
their motives are clear.
真相が明らかになるまで
動くべきでは ありません
The situation is not simple enough to allow
for a purely emotional response.
事は 感情で動いていいほど 単純では無い
Your "reasoning" makes me wanna vomit.
へどが出そうな正論だな
If vomiting will satisfy you,
then vomit as much as you like.
へどを吐くだけで良いのなら
幾らでも吐きなさい
If that would resolve this,
I'd consider it a cheap price to pay.
その程度で済めば
安いものです
Brother! Give me the order!
Let me avenge them all!
兄者
俺に命令を
皆の敵を
Be quiet.
静まれ
兄者！
Brother, they were all slaughtered!
皆 殺されたんだぞ！
Silence.
黙れ
おやっさんたちを殺されて
何とも思わないのかっ！
Pops and everyone got killed!
Don't you care!?
SHUT UP!
黙れぇ！
黙れ
Silence...
Care to join me for a little drink?
少し
付き合ってもらえませんかしら？
奴らは なぜ 撤退しなかった？
Why didn't those men retreat?
They must have known what was coming
from the moment they were boxed in.
足を封じられた時点で
ああなることは 目に見えていたはずだ
What reason could have possibly compelled
them to go so far, even to their own deaths?
死を賭してでも
あそこまでする理由が
あるとでもいうのか
あれは
They were dead men.
死人ですわね
Dead men?
死人？
They had already accepted their fates.
彼らは 既に死を受け入れていました
Therefore, they were as good as dead.
すなわち 死人
They fear no traps, they do not cower,
they do not withdraw.
だから どんな罠も恐れない
ひるまない 引かない
My lord, what did you ever do to have
instilled such deep hatred within them?
彼らから あれほどまでに
深い恨みを買うとは
オゥルォは いったい何をされましたの？
分からない
I don't know.
You don't know?
分からない？
私は
I had lost my memories and was lying
wounded when Eruruu saved me.
記憶を失って倒れていたところを
エルルゥたちに助けられた
So, I don't know.
だから
分からない
I don't know what I've done up to now,
自分が これまで何をしてきたのか
or even who I really am.
自分が 何者なのかすらも
The attack from Kuccha Keccha has
left some countries wavering.
クッチャ・ケッチャの襲撃で
各国は だいぶ揺れているようです
A number of them wish to
reconsider the alliance.
同盟について 考え直したいと
言って来た国も
Just our luck to have them attack us
at a time like this.
よりによって こんな時に攻めて来るとは
Or could this have been their motive?
もしや それが奴らの狙い？
P... Pardon me!
も 申し上げます！
Our messenger to Kuccha Keccha
has returned!
クッチャ・ケッチャからの
使いの者が戻りましたー！
あはっ
馬鹿野郎！
Don't die on me now, you fool!
勝手に くたばるんじゃねえ！
What are you!?
てめえは何だ？
勤めを果たさずに くたばる腰抜けかあ！
Some kind of weakling that's gonna go
before your mission's complete?
男なら 見事 勤めを果たしてみやがれえ！
If you're a man, then let's see you
complete this mission of yours!
Kuccha Keccha... we, your servants...
クッチャ・ケッチャ… は あぁ…
う 我ら 使者… 襲撃… うう
All attacked... everyone but me...
じ 自分を 残し… う ん 皆ー
They all perished...
討ち死にぃー！ うう…
Please avenge us!
どうか
敵をっ
Well done.
よくやった
You accomplished your mission admirably.
よく 勤めを果たしたな
Now you can go proudly too.
これで お前も 胸を張ってゆけるぜ
We're breaking away.
決裂だ
Benawi, you have no complaints, do you?
ベナウィ
文句は無いな？
No, as you wish, my lord.
はい
御心のままに
Gather all troops!
全軍に知らせよ！
We're moving on Kuccha Keccha!
クッチャ・ケッチャに進軍する！
Show them just how much
this has cost them!
この代償が いかに高いものか
奴らに思い知らせてやれ！
Roger!
Father...
お父さん
What's the matter?
どうした？
Father, you're scaring me.
お父さん 怖い
Scaring you? I am?
怖い？
私が？
I don't like the way you're being now.
今のお父さん やだぁ
-クァー グルルルルル
-ムックル？
Mukkuru?
What's wrong, Brother?
どうしたんだ 兄者？
うぉーー！ どぅわーー！
We're surrounded!
囲まれやした
んっ ぐっ 方円陣！
Form a circle!
やーー！ どぅわー！
-うっ わっ！ うん！
-おわぁ うん！
ふんっ！
えいっ！
-どぉわっ！
-ぐわあー！
My name is Touka.
某が名は トウカ
In the name of justice, I shall wield
my sword for Kuccha Keccha!
義により クッチャ・ケッチャに
助太刀する
Evil Rakshain, in the name
of the Evankulga,
悪漢ラクシャインよ
エヴェンクルガの名において
I shall slay you!
切る！
ぬおお！
Rakshain?
ラクシャイン？
Brother!
兄者ー！
Who are you?
何だ？ お前は
I was just starting to get bored.
丁度 退屈してたところですの
トウカ殿
Lady Touka! I appreciate your help.
助太刀 感謝するー！
Rakshain! What a surprise to meet
with you again like this!
ラクシャイン
再び そなたと このような形で
まみえることに なろうとはなあ
What?
何？
I didn't think you'd recover from those wounds,
but I see you still live, Rakshain.
あれだけの手傷
よもや助かるまいと思うたが
生きていたか ラクシャイン
Brother-in-law, traitor!
我が義弟にして 裏切り者よ！
けっ あふぅ
その罪 死をもって償うがいい
You shall pay for your crimes with your life!
はぁはは はぁ…
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
孤独の中求む
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼 祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼 弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす 輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし 詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
Unrest